Finding Aid for the Eugene Paul Nassar/Arthur Mizener Correspondence
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Eugene Paul Nassar/Arthur Mizener Correspondence
1965-1991
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0571
.21 linear feet
Biography/History
Eugene Paul Nassar, a native of Utica, New York, is professor emeritus of English and founder of the Ethnic Heritage Studies Center at Utica College of Syracuse University. He is a former Rhodes Scholar who in 1962 completed his doctoral degree at Cornell University. He is the author of books on Wallace Stevens, Ezra Pound, Dante and two books of literary essays. Nassar’s collection of prose poems, Wind of the Land, was published in 1979. He has also written numerous articles for scholarly journals.
Scope and Content
This .21 linear feet collection contains 28 pieces of correspondence either by or about Arthur Mizener. The correspondence is arranged by year in 13 file folders. The subject matter ranges from publishing, to literary criticism, to poetry, to family, and health.
- Correspondence
  - from Arthur Mizener to Gene Nassar, June 29, 1965
  - from Arthur Mizener to Gene Nassar, May 23, 1966
  - from Arthur Mizener to Gene Nassar, October 10, 1966
  - from Arthur Mizener to Gene Nassar, 1966
  - from Arthur Mizener to Gene Nassar, February 10, 1967
  - from Arthur Mizener to Gene Nassar, November 11, 1968
  - from Arthur Mizener to Gene Nassar, August 5, 1970
  - from Mike Abrams to Gene Nassar, April 6, 1971
  - from Bernhard Kendler to Gene Nassar, April 23, 1971
  - from Arthur Mizener to Gene Nassar, July 10, 1971
  - from Mike Abrams to Gene Nassar w/attachment, July 28, 1971
  - from Gene Nassar to Mike Abrams, August 18, 1971
  - from Mike Abrams to Gene Nassar, September 13, 1971
  - from Gene Nassar to W. W. Morton w/attachment, September 16, 1971
  - from Mike Abrams to Gene Nassar, October 14, 1971
  - from Mike Abrams to Gene Nassar, February 17, 1972
  - from Gene Nassar to Bernhard Kendler, February 22, 1972
  - from Arthur Mizener to Gene Nassar, June 14, 1972
  - from Arthur Mizener to Gene Nassar, June 26, 1972
  - from Arthur Mizener to Gene Nassar, October 4, 1972
  - from Arthur Mizener to Gene Nassar, March 13, 1973
  - from John Francis to Gene Nassar, January 9, 1974
  - from Kenney Withers to Gene Nassar, January 22, 1974
  - from Arthur Mizener to Gene Nassar, October 15, 1974
  - from Arthur Mizener to Gene Nassar, December 4, 1975
  - from Arthur Mizener to Gene Nassar, September 21, 1977
  - from Mike Abrams to Gene Nassar, October 24, 1990
  - from Rosemary Colt to Gene Nassar, January 29, 1991